Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil: for thou art with me.
In the beginning three were created
Man; made of clay
Angels; made of light
And the third; made of fire...
Called the "Jinn"
Created with free will; this third race
rule the world for thousands of years
When man was given the dominion over the earth
A sect of Jinn, known as Shiantii became resentful,
Believing the sons of Adam were nothing more than savages,
For centuries, the Shiantii have been laying in wait
But there were a few who were watching....
Guardians who sworn their blood line to protect men; and all that is good
And ensure that darkness never over takes this world
Man has all but forgotten that Jinn ever existed
It's time for him to remember
India, 1901
God protect me from Satan the damned.
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
Duivelaanbidder ...(Cursed Devil)
you have something that is not yours.
And I'm here to get it back.
You may keep your body. His soul is already dead.
But give that girl back.
God protect me from Satan the damned.
In the name of God, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful.
They bury this body in the name of the enemy.
He belongs to me now
Give her back and I leave you alone.
You know I just want the girl.
Jehangir...!
Did you think, you could lure me into a trap?
God protect me from Satan the damned.....
Your God has abandoned you, man!
Listen to my words:
I'm going after the children one by one,
Generation after generation,
And murder them in your name!
Asshole, son of a bitch...
>
Ann Arbor, Michigan, Gegenwart
Hi, I am looking for a Mr. Amen
Oh, you've got the wrong address;
this is the Walker's resident.
That’s right, Walker; sorry
It has been a really long day.
No signature required.
Okay ... Thank you!
- I think you've got a birthday present.
- It's not my birthday!
Someone think it is, and it's so pretty...
- Who in the world wrapped this?
- There is no name, no address...
Come to think of it; I don't have to sign for it either.
- Oh; Great. - Very strange.
Happy Birthday, Shan
Ok, this is bizarre. A VHS...?
What if a dirty video?
We sold our VCR, how are we supposed to watch it?
- I had a VCR in my office. - Of course you did...
No! No...No...No not again...! Oh Dinner!
- You were not allowed to laugh. - Okay, I'm sorry.
Let me take you out for dinner, you look beautiful tonight.
Please let me just show you off tonight.
How have I done this again...?
Ok; I can fix this...
Oh, yeah that thing have been there for the past two days.
It's kind of creeping me out,
but I think it's just those cardboard cutter.
Shawn...?
Do you hear me, baby?
Hello...?
Honey?
Oh Baby, are you okay?
Its ok, you're safe.
Someone house is burning.
I heard my mother.
Who's there?
Who's there...?
Gabriel...
Thank God!
- I thought it come early tonight.
- Message have been delivered.
- Thank you, Gabriel.
- No need for thanks, Ali.
It is important for all of us.
You're right. Let's pray and believe it's.
So Jess, get this, with all the orders we
got for Firebreather this week,
George said I could design the Firebreather 2
And the best part
He’s giving me that raise.
Oh, I like George...
So a...
That conversation we had last week.
I think we're ready,
I think it's time.
Jess...
Hey, honey...?
Jess?
- Hey baby, are you okay? - Yeah. I'm ok.
What's wrong?
I have something I want to tell you but...
I just don't know how...
Ok whatever it is, we work it out,
we work through, we always do...
I can't have kids..., Shawn.
What are you talking about...?
I mean it's impossible, I can't have kids.
How long did you know?
Oh...Well...
I know I should told you, but...
I was afraid, if you knew...
That you wouldn't want to be with me...
Oh. I didn't want to lie to you...
Shawn
If you watching this right now...
Means we haven't seen each other for a very long time
I'm very sorry about that
Because it means you grew up just like I do,
without your father...
But we don't have that much time
And you really need to listen to me very carefully.
Everything I've done and everything I'm about to do
I did to protect you and your mother...
always remember that...
Strange things are gonna start happening to you
Just like they happened to me
There are things out there Shawn,
I didn't even know existed.
But they are real
And they can be very evil...
If this tape have found you...
It means you have friends...
Find them.
Learn everything you need to learn and get stronger
You have it in your blood Shawn, Just like I do
But if you're watching this right now,
It means I wasn't strong enough
But maybe you are.
That’s you,
Hey buddy, how ya doin? Can I get a toy?
Thank you
I love you too
I gave this to you on your last birthday
I love you so much, Shawn...
And I don't even know if you'll remember my face;
Or if you remember who I am.
But this is your father speaking; Shawn;
And I'm telling you to fight it
Fight 'till you can't fight it anymore
For all the one I miss...
Happy Birthday, Shawn
And good luck....
Hey honey it's me...
I just watch the video...and duh....
I gotta talk to you.
I'm sorry.
About earl... Just call me back, okay?
Okay.
Jasmine!
Jas! Honey, can you hear me?
Sweaty pick up the phone!
Jas! Jas! Where are you, Honey?
Jas, are you here? Sweetheart!
911, what's your emergency?
Yes... my wife is missing? My house has been ransacked
I need an officer here now! Please...!
Just so we're clear, there isn't anything missing,
In last you saw your wife a few hours ago?
And this fight you have, it’s not physical right?
I was upset, she was crying, I left...
Hey, is that your wife?
Oh my God....
Shawn!
Jasmine...
I thought something happened to you, I kept calling...
I was. I was... I went for a walk.
I just came home, you weren't here,
I saw this, I freaked out
- I'm so sorry, gentlemen ... - It's not a problem.
Probably just a couple of drunk frat boys,
nothing to worry about ok?
Alright, you folks have a good night.
- Goodnight. - Thank you.
- You're okay? - Yes, I...
- Did I leave the door open? - No...
No, it was locked;
they said its lock there is no force entry...
I don't know.
- Hey, no more call tonight?
- Yeah, my thought exactly.
Hey come here come sit for a sec.
Shawn, you know I love you more
than anything in this world.
- I love you too babe. - And...
Your happiness is my happiness...
And so...
Even if that means...
That you're happy with somebody else...
- Jas... - No, Shawn...
You want a family!
That’s ok.
You will have...
I wouldn't want to take it away from you...
So I'm...
I'm totally prepared to let you go.
I love you.
- I know... - Always...
You.
Only you.
I'm Sorry...
Jas!
- Jas!! - Baby...?
Come here.
- Come here. - Are you okay?
Look.
I came to get an orange juice,
I don't know what's going on, baby.
I don’t know what's going on. We put this all back,
We put it all back!
Shawn...
Come on. Grab your stuff! Let's get out of here!
Hello?
Are you safe?
Wowo... Who is this?
Get to the Cathedral at Road Long Lake
Who is this?
Now's not the time. Get there now!!
Shawn...
Yeah...
My name is Gabriel.
Jasmine...
Don't be afraid, you're safe within this wall.
They can’t get to you here.
Wait. What? What can't get to us here?
How do you know who we are?
Can you please tell me what the hell is going on?
Watch your language in my church, please...
The Big Guy gets pissed.
Ok, can somebody tell us what's going on please?
- You watch the tape didn't you?
- Yeah... Wait, how do you know about that?
I'm was the one holding it for you all this years.
- Ok yeah, well, but I don't believe it.
- Then why are you here?
- I don't know. - Yes you do.
Your instinct brought you here.
We can't help you on this unless you believe.
Believe in what?
You need to know who you’re fighting.
So you can fight back.
Ok...; how did you do that?
Jas, tell me how most people would explain what just happened?
Magic. That was a simple magic tricks.
- A ghosts, I don't know? - Ghost...?
Ghosts, demons, poltergeist... They don’t exist.
Something else, the one solitary answer for everything
You cannot explained.
You see...
In the beginning... Three were created.
Man made of clay...
Angels made of light...
And the third, made of fire called the Jinn.
That what's coming for you.
Is he serious? I'm Sorry... Come on this is crazy.
Ok. So, if these things are real,
Then how come we've never even heard of them?
Have you read the Torah Shawn?
Or as some people call it...
The Old Testament. From the Prophet Ezekiel.
"And out of the midst of the fire, came a
Poor living creature with the likeness of men’s."
"Their appearance was like burning coals of fire."
"At the centre of which looks like a molten metal."
"And the living creature moved with the appearance
Of a flash of lightning."
They have been around for a long time.
The Jinn were here first.
And some of them want the world back.
They're jealous of our imagination.
Of our incredible capacity to create.
Why do they after us?
Within the Jinn there is a prophecy.
Very few of us know about it.
But your great grandfather did.
You're part of their prophecy.
And they are afraid of you.
This guys are crazy, Shawn. Come on let's go.
Shawn, we can help you fight this.
You're gonna have to listen to us.
Yeah, well...
This isn't exactly the kind of help we looking for.
Wait.
Here.
If you get into trouble, use it.
OK great... Thank you.
You can cut tomatoes with this.
Remember... remember you're safe
Within the walls of any house of God.
Okay, thank you.
Ask the Walkers about Father Westhoff.
- What did you just say?
- Ask the Walkers about me.
Ma..! Dad..! It's Shawn, open up.
Your father...
Passed away a long time ago, Shawn.
That tape was made 25 years ago.
And he's saying stuff that doesn't make any senses.
Then we went and met up with this two guys...
They are telling us we're in great danger and a
Bunch of other crazy shits that I’ve never even heard of.
Shawn... Honey... I don't understand
What are you talking about now?
Weird stuff is happening to us Ma, and...
I don't know if it's a prank,
Whether or not to believe these guys...
- What weird stuff?
- Our house was vandalised.
- What?
- There's this thing looking at us from another apartment.
This tape comes out of nowhere and
These guys telling us it’s all real and...
- Something after us.
- What... What after you?
I don't know... arghh... Jinn.
What?
- You know what that is? - No.
But the priest who arrange for us to adopt you...
He made us promise that you will always wear your necklace...
And there were something about a verse and the Jinn...
I don't know...
I always thought it was a good luck charm, or something...
- Okay, what is his name? - Westhoff.
Father Westhoff.
Shawn! Please don't go!
Baby, my father told me to find the people who can help me.
If what they are saying is true, I don't have much time.
We can keep talking about this.
But we can run! Baby, we can hide it!
- I'm not the type to hide, you know that.
- Shawn!
Please don't leave me.
I'm never gonna leave you.
I love you.
I know.
Jasmine!
Jasmine...
We're missing something, something big.
I know. We can't keep him against his will.
It is possible when the child is born.
It's not what I expected... maybe...
It wants to end the blood line once and for all.
I pray that is not the line prophecies
- You've never been wrong all this years.
- We are not wrong, Gabriel.
He doesn't believe... He's going to die.
The sons of Adam will fall...
The Jinn will rise...
And this world will be ours again.
No matter what I did you will not summit.
You don't need to die...
You say that... they would fear me.
It didn't seem afraid.
They are afraid of what you can become.
What do you mean "What I could become"?
There was a prophecy, recorded in a text called the "Jinn Scrolls".
It was lost a long time.
But it said that in a battle between man and Jinn
One shall emerged more powerful than both.
And will lead the world into a golden age.
You think it talks about me?
I do.
Shawn! Where are you?
Get out of the house, Shawn!
Shawn, listen to me whatever you hear,
Stay out of the house. I love you.
I got him... Get out of the house!
Shawn!
- You get a good sleep? - Hopping it's all a dream.
I wish it was, but right now we are running against the clock.
We need to get some more answer.
And there's only one men who can help us.
There is a sect of Jinn called Shiantii.
Worshipers of Satan.
The Shiantii are very powerful.
Even the rest of the Jinn are afraid of them.
If they are so powerful, how can I fight them?
Men with strong will, heart and mind I can sense them.
The strongest can fight them, and the strongest can...
Destroy them...
But the last one lived a hundred years ago.
Jehangir Amin, your great grandfather.
He tried to safe a girl,
Who has taken by the same Shiantii that’s after you.
- Cars fast. - Oh, Yeah.
But can I outrun the Jinn?
- How you doin? I came to see Ali Amin, room 413.
- Signed here.
- Step this way, arms up
- All right Good.
- Gentlemen, why don't you follow me...
Shawn, come on.
It is hard to believe that the one person
Who could help us find Jasmine is in here.
Well appearances can be deceiving.
Hey, how do you do the thing with the pen?
Magnet.
Alright gentlemen, right this way.
Follow me.
I guess I remember this one, he's dangerous.
Spook up a patients, so we have to put him in solitary.
And we're right here in the right.
Just bang the door if you need anything.
He looks just like his father.
Come here.
It's okay.
Sit down.
Look too my eyes.
I will hunt down your children, one by one,
Generation after generation,
And murder them in your name!
I am
Shawn...
He looks just like his father
He doesn't believe, he's gonna die
Where does it come from for sure?
But I don't have that much time
Listen to me very carefully.
Everything I've done...
I did to protect you and your mother...
There are things out there Shawn...
And it can be very evil
You had it in your blood, Shawn, just like I do.
You know that I love you more than anything in this worlds
I'm Jasmine...
And your happiness is my happiness. ..
You want a family...
I wouldn't want to take it away from you...
What do you scared off...?
Listen... Closely...
Do you understand now?
Did you hear the heartbeat?
It came from inside
The come for you because you have a child.
Some of them you can see, the way I can.
And they come, generation after generation
Looking for the prophesied one.
Caring the father, to wait and see if the son is the one they looking for.
There are only a few bloodlines in the world who can fulfil the prophecy.
No... That’s impossible. She told me she can't have children.
She may not know... But make no mistake.
She carries... your son.
How much more time we waste?
The boy must take the test! He must pass the Chilla!
The test? What test?
See what I see.
Feel...
What I feel.
- Where am I? - A memory...
Of an ancestor.
- It feels so real...
- Because it is. In your mind.
There’s more than one dimension in this world.
And you will need to move between them...
In order to pass the Chilla.
So this is the test?
Do not let fear overtake you.
If you do, you will end up like me.
I've failed my Chilla. I let them into my mind.
And they've tormented me ever since.
Because I tried to stop them.
Stop them from doing what?
From coming to you.
Because, Shawn...
I am a son of Jehangir too.
I'm your uncle.
- Why didn't anyone tell me?
- He don't want you to see him like this.
He’s been here since your parents died...
Waiting...
Jasmine...?
The baby?
Yeah.
You have to come here, and feel it for yourself.
So, this Chilla... What if I fail?
You cannot fail.
Oh my God...
They’ve been listening.
Run! Get out of here! Both of you, Get the hell out!
They've come! Run!!!
Run!!!
Come on!
Run! Run!
Run!!!
Shawn, look out!
Shawn, get out of here now!
Don't stop, go!
Listen, don't turn back, no matter what you see.
Run! Go now!
Go!
Shit!
Go!!!!
"For our battle not against flesh and blood"
"But against the lord and empires of this age".
"Therefore put on the armour of God"
"So that when the day evil comes,"
"You may stand your grounds and after all has done"
Father, what was he?
Gabriel, is a Jinn.
One of the few who work for humanity.
Who do you think brought you to me?
When your parents were killed?
You have two choices.
You can stay protected within the walls of the church,
Or you can end this.
- How do I end this?
- You are going to find out.
The Chilla can allowed you to get
Close enough to the Shiantii
To exploit their weaknesses.
The Chilla
Is a window into their world.
You can go where they go,
See what they see, do what they do.
Do you have the knife?
Yes.
This blade is made from the metal forged in Jinn fire.
One of a few... like the pendant on your necklace.
It doesn't fully exist in our dimension.
But this can cut into theirs.
But, before you can wield it properly,
You will have to pass the Chilla.
The Chilla is a test.
Physical, mental and spiritual test.
Of Fear.
Of fears unique to you.
Because they arises within you.
From your own memories...
From your own darkest thoughts.
No one, not even me, can prepare you for what you will face.
But there are some things that can help you.
Please kneel
Both knees.
You will need Zamzam water.
Holy water from Mecca, that saved the son of Abraham.
Its power is a gift for men,
But even diluted can harm those made of fire.
For the Shiantii jinn, it is like poison.
The verse on the Jinn written or spoken can weaken them.
You can trap them.
Once you recite the verse...
Exactly as I'm going to teach it to you, the Chilla will begin.
And then what?
And they will come.
Find an uninhibited place where your mind can't be trick.
Do not brake your concentration even for a moment.
They will use everything you fear
To keep you from completing your Chilla.
To the Shiantii jinn,
The weak mind are just flash and bones.
But those that achieve a higher understanding...
They are feared.
If you awake from the Chilla
With your mind intact,
You’ll know what to do next.
Oh shit...
I know you don't want me to do this.
So why not just leave us alone?
I will never leave you alone.
I will hunt you down 'till the Day of Judgment.
When this world will be ours again!
Run!
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
Shawn?
Hello?
Shawn...
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
Shawn no...
Oh God, please tell me you haven't started.
Shawn baby, I escaped.
Father Westhoff told me where you are,
You don't have to do this.
Please, Shawn
They are way too strong for you.
Oh my God...
Something’s coming.
Baby! Look at me!
Look into my eyes - this is not a test.
Please, look at me!
O God, they are coming...!
Please, Shawn, they're gonna kill us!
Help me...
Shawn, look what they've done to me...
Look at me!
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
You're a coward...
Just like your father.
Look at what you've done to your child.
Look...
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
Why are you doing this?
Why are you?
Everyone you loved is gone...
And, just as in the beginning...
There’s only me.
I've always been there.
Always known what you could've become.
We could offer you so much more.
You could be king...
With a thousand heirs.
From a thousand Jasmine.
I only want one.
Mine.
Now where is she?
There is a war coming, Shawn.
Neither man nor Jinn could stop it.
Maybe not.
But I only want to stop you.
You step out of your circle.
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
You've come to play again.
Oh no...
Not tonight.
My Chilla ends now.
And tonight...
You all fall.
You’ll never see me.
See if you can hide Jinn.
I show mercy, offered you power...
Now I give you death!
Come and get me.
My Lord, please protect this men.
I'll do my part so you can do Yours.
Come alive and help me babe come on.
Come on, he got nothing on us.
Come on, show me some tricks baby, come on!
You want some of me?
Come get me.
Come on!
Come on, baby... Come on...
Hold it together.
Come get me!
So
This fight is between your master and the boy alone.
I've wielded this against many of you over the years.
Do you want to play?
Let's finish this.
Nice, Westhoff...
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
Now, Shawn!
Shawn, hurry!
Get that!
Dammn you! Come on!
Uncle!
Shawn...
I seek refuge in Allah from Shaitan, the accursed one.
Papa?
Wake up...
Sons of Jehangir...
You've made me an enemy of one of the Shiantii
Do not make enemies of us all.
You have the power...
But you're not an angel...
Where’s my wife?
Where’s my wife!?
Okay who's next?
Come on!
Where is she?
Where is my wife?
Where is she...?
Jasmine...?
Baby?
Come here.
Look at you... Thank God.
Babe.
He done it for me didn't he?
His job is to protect you and your son.
No matter what the cost.
If you knew we were hiding on,
They would've known.
I love you.
A year later
Everything is ready!
- Oh Thank you, uncle; what can I do?
- Oh I've got this.
- A new recipe?
- No actually, an old one.
My brother thought me this.
- Ahh... it’s for later, its dessert.
- Ermmm... Fabulous!
But not as sweet as you, my little ushiuu!
Oh...okay...
You're an angel, come look at you...
Alright...
You gonna have to teach me how to do this.
I don't think Shawn liked the idea of his ​​mom cooking.
Funny? I'm learning. You do not get a piece.
My baby angel...
- I'll get that.
- I got it.
Daddy got's it.
I thought you gave that up. A long time ago...
Come across death made you think.
You could have gone Christian you know?
The point is... Something happen.
There's something that wouldn't let me go.
There's nothing strange about that.
I see that in my business all the time.
I don't.
You were guarding that boy;
Since he was a child, without him ever knowing it.
You think something is guarding you as well?
Hard to believe.
That's why we call it a "miracles".
It's a good symbol, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Well you earned it, Gabriel.